Saya Kim-Suzuki

New York City Metropolitan Area



sayakimsuzuki@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/saya-kim-suzuki

Summary

I'm 17-year-old student excited to take on climate change, technology, and ethics, especially their intersection. I'm endlessly curious and will probably ask you a million questions if I could.

At The Knowledge Society, I am actively learning about IoT and AI because I am inspired by the potential that tech has to steer the next generation of environmentalism and society.

I am also a softball pitcher, love backpacking, and can bake a killer mocha French macaron!

Sign up for my newsletter: https://landing.mailerlite.com/webforms/landing/h9g8c3

Experience

πs Innovator

The Knowledge Society (TKS)

Sep 2020 - Present (6 months +)

Immersed in an environment surrounded by ambitious teens who are training to impact billions.

Researching emerging tech while working towards becoming unicorn people through public speaking, communication, and networking!

IIII Researcher

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020 (2 months)

Worked with the MIT PiPACT Research Institute to devise a privatized solution to COVID-19 Bluetooth contact tracing.

- Learned from mentors from Harvard Health and MIT Lincoln Laboratory.
- Collected data for Received Signal Strength Indicator (RSSI) between two devices under various conditions such as distance or obstruction.
- Wrote a report summarizing results from a fabric obstruction experiment to simulate devices in pockets.

Education



Ethical Culture Fieldston School

High School Diploma 2017 - 2021

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Autonomous Cognitive Assistant Summer Program 2020 - 2020

Developed proficiency in Python and machine learning by building neural networks from scratch. Utilizing audio, visual, and natural language processing techniques, built programs:

- Song recognition (like Shazam)
- Picture classification by face
- Image search

columbia University in the City of New York

High School College Edge Program

2020 - 2021

Took Calculus III (multivariable) alongside undergraduates.



Migh Mountain Institute

2019 - 2019

A semester school in Leadville, Colorado with eco-inspired curricula including Natural Science, Environmental Ethics, and Literature of the Natural World. Two 18-day backpacking trips: One in the Colorado mountains and the second in the canyons of Utah, where I was selected Student Expedition Leader.



ᄍ University of Pennsylvania

Engineering Summer at Penn: Robotics

2019 - 2019

4-week Intensive program covering a college-level mechatronics course. Developed a piano-playing robot after learning the basics of electrical engineering and computer science principles.

Skills

Ethics • Leadership • Communication • Calculus • Writing • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Environmental Awareness • Internet of Things (IoT) • Web Development • Python (Programming Language)